Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Heaney, Seamus, 1939-
Manuscript Collection No. 960
51 linear ft. (102 boxes) and 13 oversized papers (OP)
Personal papers of Irish poet Seamus Heaney consisting mostly of correspondence, as well as some literary manuscripts, printed material, subject files, photographs, audio-visual material, and personal papers from 1951-2004.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 2003.
Restrictions on access
Special restrictions apply: Series 1, Correspondence, is closed to researchers.
Biographical Note
Seamus Heaney was born on April 13, 1939, to Margaret and Patrick Heaney. The eldest of nine children, he was born at the family farm, Mossbawn, northwest of Belfast in County Derry. He attended the local school at Anahorish until 1957 when he enrolled at Queens College, Belfast, where he studied English. After graduation he taught English at St. Joseph's College in Belfast.
While at St. Joseph's he began to write, publishing work in university magazines under the pseudonym Incertus. During that time, he joined a poetry workshop organized by Philip Hobsbaum. In 1965, in connection with the Belfast Festival, he published Eleven Poems, and in August of that year he married Marie Devlin. The following year he became a lecturer in modern English literature at Queens College; his first son, Michael, was born; and Faber and Faber published Death of a Naturalist. This collection earned him the Eric Gregory Award, the Cholmondeley Award, the Somerset Maugham Award, and the Geoffrey Faber Memorial Prize. Marie and Seamus Heaney's second son, Christopher, was born in 1968.
Door Into the Dark, published in 1969, was a Poetry Book Society Choice for the year. In 1970-1971, Heaney was guest lecturer at the University of California, Berkeley. He returned to Northern Ireland in 1971, and in 1972 he resigned his lectureship at Queens College, moved his family to Glanmore, in County Wicklow, and published Wintering Out. In 1973 his daughter Catherine Ann was born. During this year he also received the Denis Devlin Award and the Writer in Residence Award from the American Irish Foundation. In 1975 North was published, winning the E.M. Forster Award and the Duff Cooper Memorial Prize. During these years at Glanmore, Heaney also gave many readings in the United States and England and edited two poetry anthologies.
In 1975 Heaney began teaching at Carysfort College in Dublin, and in 1976 he and his family moved to Sandymount in the city. In 1979 Heaney published Field Work and in 1980 Selected Poems and Preoccupations. In 1981 he gave up his position at Carysfort to become visiting professor at Harvard. In 1982 he won the Bennett Award and Queens University awarded him an honorary Doctor of Letters. He co-founded Field Day Company with the playwright Brian Friel and others in 1983. Station Island, his first collection in five years, was published in 1984. During that year he was elected Boylston Professor of Rhetoric and Oratory at Harvard. That same year his mother died.
In 1988 Seamus Heaney visited Emory University where he inaugurated the Richard Ellmann Lectures in Modern Literature. These lectures were collected and published as The Place of Writing in 1989. In 1991 Heaney published a new collection Seeing Things, followed by the Redress of Poetry in 1995. In the fall of that year, Heaney was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature.
In recent years Heaney has been recipient of numerous awards and prizes. His translation of Beowulf (1999) won the Whitbread Award for best book of the year, and his Finders Keepers (2002) won the Truman Capote Award for Literary Criticism. He also has been awarded a number of honorary degrees; he is a member of Aosdana, the Irish Academy of Artist and Writers, and is a Foreign Member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters. In addition, he has been made a Comandeur de L’Ordre des Arts et Lettres by the French Ministry of Culture.
Scope and Content Note
The Seamus Heaney papers consist of correspondence, literary manuscripts, printed material, subject files, photographs, audio-visual material, and personal papers from 1951-2004. Correspondence (1963-2004) comprises the bulk of the collection and documents Heaney’s relationship with his students, publishers, friends, and other literary figures, including Joseph Brodsky, Donald Davie, Seamus Deane, Douglas Dunn, Peter Fallon, Brian Friel, Anthony Hecht, Ted Hughes, Michael Longley, Medbh McGuckian, Paul Muldoon, and James Simmons. Literary manuscripts include a small group of poems and prose written by Heaney and many manuscripts sent to him by other literary figures and by aspiring writers. Printed material, either written by or about Seamus Heaney is present as are other printed items collected by him. Small groups of subject files, audio-visual material, and personal papers are included as well as a large group of photographs from 1951-2003.
Arrangement Note
Organized into eight series: (1) Correspondence, (2) Writings by others, (3) Printed material, (4) Subject files, (5) Photographs, (6) Audio-visual material, (7) Personal papers, and (8) Writings by Seamus Heaney.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Banville, John; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-; Dawe, Gerald, 1952-; Deane, Seamus, 1940-; Dunn, Douglas;. Fallon, Peter, 1951-; Friel, Brian.; Hecht, Anthony, 1923-; Hughes, Ted, 1930-1998.; Longley, Michael, 1939-; McGuckian, Medbh, 1950-; Muldoon, Paul.; Simmons, James, 1933-
Topical Terms
English poetry--Irish authors.; Poets, Irish.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Poems.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Occupation
Poet.
Related Materials in This Repository
Ciaran Carson papers, Peter Fallon-The Gallery Press collection, Ted Hughes papers, Michael Longley papers, Derek Mahon papers, Medbh McGuckian papers, Seamus Heaney collection, Charles Monteith collection, Paul Muldoon papers, Frank Ormsby papers, Tom Paulin papers, Ron Schuchard papers, and James Simmons papers.
Description of Series
- Correspondence, 1963-2004, Series 1; Boxes 1 - 64
  Scope and Content Note
  The correspondence series contains general correspondence, literary correspondence, outgoing correspondence, and other correspondence from 1963-2004. The extensive collection of correspondence is arranged chronologically with the bulk falling between 1978 and 2002. Many of the letters relate to speaking and reading engagements, queries from aspiring writers, requests for recommendations, and letters from admirers of Heaney's work. Also present in the collection is an important group of letters from his friends and literary associates (1964-2003), notably John Banville, Joseph Brodsky, Seamus Deane, Douglas Dunn, Peter Fallon, Tom Flanagan, Brian Friel, Philip Hobsbaum, Ted Hughes, Brendan Kennelly, Thomas Kilroy, Michael Longley, Medbh McGuckian, Derek Mahon, John Montague, Paul Muldoon, Bernard O'Donoghue, Tom Paulin, and Derek Walcott. A small amount of literary correspondence from these and other individuals accompany writings and is found attached to those writings in the Writings by Others series.
  Included in this series is a large group of outgoing letters (1967-2003), in the original holograph or typescript and signed by Heaney, which were sent by telefacsimile. There are also invitations, letters of recommendation, and letters from many of Heaney's publishers. The series documents Heaney's writing career as well as his relationships with many students, literary colleagues, and friends.
  Restrictions on access
  Special restrictions apply: Series 1, Correspondence, is closed to researchers.
  Arrangement Note
  Organized into four subseries: (1.1) General correspondence, (1.2) Literary correspondence, (1.3) Outgoing correspondence, and (1.4) Other correspondence.
  - General correspondence, 1963-2003, Subseries 1.1; Boxes 1 - 36
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1970 January-September (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1970 October-December (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1972 January-June (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1972 July-October (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1972 November-December (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1973 January-March and undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1973 April-December (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1978 January-May (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1978 June-December (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1979 January-March (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1979 April-December (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - [ca. 1980s] (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1980 January-June (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1980 July-December (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1981 January-March (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1981 April-July (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1981 August-December (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1982 January-February (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1982 March-April (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1982 May-July (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1982 August-September (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1982 October-December (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - [ca.1983] (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1983 January-February (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 1983 March-April (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 1983 May (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 1983 June-July (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 1983 August-September (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1983 October-November (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 1983 December (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 1984 January (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1984 February (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1984 March-April (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1984 May-June (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1984 July-August (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1984 September-October (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1984 November-December (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1985 January (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1985 February-March (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1985 April-May (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1986 June-July (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1985 August (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1985 September-October (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 1985 November-December (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 1986 January (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 1986 February-March (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 1986 April-May (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 1986 June (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1986 July (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1986 August-September (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1986 October-November (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1986 December (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1987 January-February (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1987 March-April (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1987 May (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1987 June (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1987 July-August (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1987 September-October (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1987 November-December (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1988 January-February (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1988 March-April (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1988 May-June (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1988 July-August (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1988 September (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1988 October (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1988 November (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1988 December (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - [ca. 1989] (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1989 January (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1989 February 1-20 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1989 February 21-28 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1989 March (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 1989 April (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - 1989 April [Fiftieth birthday cards] (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - 1989 May (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1989 June (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1989 July (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - 1989 August (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - 1989 September (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - 1989 October (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1989 November (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 1989 December (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - [ca. 1990s] (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 1990 January-February (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - 1990 March (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1990 April (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1990 May (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1990 June (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1990 July (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1990 August (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1990 September 1-19 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1990 September 20-30 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 1990 October (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1990 November-December (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - [ca. 1991] (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1991 January-February (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1991 March (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1991 April (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1991 May-June (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 1991 July-August (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1991 September-October (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1991 November (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1991 December (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - [ca. 1992] (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1992 January (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1992 February (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1992 March (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1992 April (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1992 May (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1992 June (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1992 July (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1992 August (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1992 September (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1992 October (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1992 November (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - 1992 December (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - [ca. 1993] (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1993 January (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1993 February (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 1993 March (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1993 April (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1993 May (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 1993 June (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 1993 July (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1993 August (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1993 September (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1993 October (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1993 November (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1993 December (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - [ca. 1994] (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1994 January (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1994 February (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 1994 March 1-14 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - 1994 March 15-31 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - 1994 April 1-11 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 1994 April 12-30 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 1994 May (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - 1994 June (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 1994 July (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1994 August (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 1994 September (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 1994 October (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 1994 November (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 1994 December (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - [ca. 1995] (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - 1995 January (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - 1995 February (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - 1995 March (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - 1995 April (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1995 May (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 1995 June (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - 1995 July (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 1995 August (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - 1995 September (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1995 October (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 1995 November (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - 1995 December (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - [ca 1996] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1996 January 1-17 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 1996 January 18-31 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - 1996 February (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - 1996 March 1-15 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - 1996 March 16-31 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - 1996 April (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - 1996 May (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - 1996 June (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1996 July (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 1996 August (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - 1996 September (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - 1996 October (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - 1996 November (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - 1996 December (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - [ca. 1997] (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - 1997 January (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 1997 February (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1997 March (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - 1997 April (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 1997 May (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 1997 June (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 1997 July (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - 1997 August (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - 1997 September (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - 1997 October (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 1997 November (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 1997 December 1-13 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - 1997 December 14-31 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - [ca.1998] (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - 1998 January (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - 1998 February (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - 1998 March (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - 1998 April (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - 1998 May (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - 1998 June (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - 1998 July (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 1998 August (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - 1998 September (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - 1998 October (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1998 November (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1998 December (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - [ca. 1999] (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 1999 January (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - 1999 February (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 1999 March (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - 1999 April (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - 1999 May (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - 1999 June (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - 1999 July (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - 1999 August (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - 1999 September (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - 1999 October (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - 1999 November (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - 1999 December (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - [ca. 2000] (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 2000 January 1-24 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - 2000 January 25-28 (Whitbread Award) [1 of 3] (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 2000 January 25-28 (Whitbread Award) [2 of 3] (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - 2000 January 25-28 (Whitbread Award) [3 of 3] (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - 2000 January 28-31 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - 2000 February (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - 2000 March (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - 2000 April (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 2000 May (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - 2000 June (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - 2000 July (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - 2000 August (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - 2000 September (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - 2000 October (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - 2000 November (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - 2000 December (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - [ca.2001] (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - 2001 January (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - 2001 February (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 2001 March (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - 2001 April 1-14 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - 2001 April 15-30 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - 2001 May (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - 2001 June (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - 2001 July (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 2001 August (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 2001 September (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - 2001 October 1-15 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - 2001 October 16-31 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - 2001 November (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - 2001 December (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - [ca. 2002] (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - 2002 January (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - 2002 February 1-11 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - 2002 February 12-28 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - 2002 March 1-14 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - 2002 March 15-31 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - 2002 April 1-16 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 2002 April 17-30 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - 2002 May (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - 2002 June (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - 2002 July 1-14 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - 2002 July 15-31 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - 2002 August 1-20 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - 2002 August 21-31 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - 2002 September 1-14 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - 2002 September 15-30 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - 2002 October 1-21 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 2002 October 22-31 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 2002 November 1-10 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - 2002 November 11-30 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - 2002 December (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - [ca. 2003] (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - 2003 January (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - 2003 February (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - 2003 March (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - 2003 April (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - 2003 May-July (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - 2003 August-September (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Undated [1 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Undated [2 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Undated [3 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Undated [4 of 4] (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Fragments (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Literary correspondence, 1964-2003, Subseries 1.2; Boxes 37 - 44
    Arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Alcorn, Alfred, 1975-2002 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Astley, Neil, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Banville, John, 1979-1998 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Bly, Robert, 1982-1984 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Boland, Eavan, ca. 1972 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Brandes, Rand, undated; 1986-2002 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, undated; 1987-1992 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Brown, George Mackay, 1968-1993 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Brownjohn, Alan, 1971-1996 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Carson, Ciaran, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Chambers, Harry, undated; 1987-1989 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Cole, William Rossa, undated, 1970-2000 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Conner, Lester, 1971-2001 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Cooke, Barrie, undated; 1971-2002 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Cooney, Seamus, 1979-1997 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Corbett, Bill, 1986-2002 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Creeley, Robert, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Crotty, Patrick, 1993-1998 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Davids, Roy, 1981-1982 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Davie, Donald, 1980-1982 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Dawe, Gerald, undated; 1981-1999 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Deane, John F., undated; 1981-2002 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Deane, Seamus, undated; 1967-1999 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Delanty, Greg, undated; 1987-2002 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Des Pres, Terrence, undated; 1982-1985 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Dorgan, Theo, 1987-2002 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Dunn, Douglas, 1970-1994 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Durcan, Paul, 1978-1999 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Eagleton, Terry, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Ellmann, Richard, 1982-1985 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Fallon, Peter, undated; 1970-1998 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Fallon, Peter, 1999-2003 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Fitzgerald, Sally, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Flanagan, Tom, 1976-2001 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Foster, Roy, 1997-2000 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Friel, Brian, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Friel, Brian, 1970-1989 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Friel, Brian, 1990-2002 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Greacen, Robert, 1995-1998 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Grennan, Eamon, undated, 1980-2001 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Hacker, Marilyn, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Hall, Donald, undated; 1979-2001 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Hamburger, Michael, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Hammond, David, undated; 1969-1979 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Hammond, David, 1980-2003 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Harper, Michael S., 1971-1998 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, Tony, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Hartnett, Michael, 1999 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Healey, Dermot, ca. 1972 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Hecht, Anthony, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Higgins, Aidan, 1984-1993 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Hildebidle, John, ca. 1969-2003 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Hill, Geoffrey, 1998 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Hobsbaum, Philip, undated; 1966-2001 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Hornback, Bert, 1970-2002 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Hughes, Frieda, 1999 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Hughes, Glyn, 1967-2001 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Hughes, Olwyn, 1973-1995 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Hughes, Ted, undated; circa 1972-1995 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Johnston, Dillon, 1983-1992 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Kavanagh, P. J., undated; 1994-1999 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Kennelly, Brendan, 1969-1999 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Kiely, Ben, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Kilroy, Thomas, 1982-2002 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Kinsella, Tom, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Korelitz, Jean Hanff, 1993-1995 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Levi, Peter, undated; 1989-1992 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Lodge, David, 1988-2000 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Longley, Edna, undated; 1980-1999 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Longley, Michael, undated; 1971-1979 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Longley, Michael, 1980-2000 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - McCabe, Bernard, undated; 1979-2002 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - McGahern, John, undated; 1971-2001 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, 1985-2001 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - McIntyre, Tom, 1971-1977 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - McLaverty, Michael, 1972-1979 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Mahon, Derek, ca. 1969-ca. 1981 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Karl, 1964-2001 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Montague, John, 1970-2001 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Monteith, Charles, undated; 1966-1989 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Morrison, Blake, undated; 1980-1994 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Motion, Andrew, 1981-2001 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Muldoon, Paul, undated; 1968-1996 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Muldoon, Paul, 1997-2003 (Box 42, Folder 10)